Someday... Yes, someday,
Algún día… Sí, algún día,
I'll be walking down
yo también
a spring path while looking up at the cherry blossoms whether I want to or not.
caminaré mientras miro cómo florecen los cerezos, quiera o no.
"Episode 12: 'Friends and Love, Love and Cherry Blossoms'"
Episodio 12: Amigas, amor y cerezos en flor
I'm a normal person.
Soy una persona normal.
I don't have the ability to touch something I can't see,
No tengo la habilidad de tocar lo que no veo
and I can't involve myself in something that's not happening right in front of me.
y no me involucro en lo que no pasa delante de mí.
What I'm scared of is while I'm not looking
Lo que temo es que, mientras no mire,
Shimamura will change into something different.
Shimamura se convierta en alguien diferente.
So I've made up my mind to spend every spare moment looking at Shimamura.
Por eso he decidido pasar cada minuto libre mirándola.
Um... Adachi.
Oye, Adachi.
Yes?
¿Qué?
Never mind.
Déjalo.
Heyo, Shima!
¡Hola, Shima!
Hey, Adachicchi is with you, too.
Vaya, Adachicchi también está aquí.
Chicchi!
¡Chicchi!
Hey, Hino and Nagafuji. It's been a while.
Vaya, Hino, Nagafuji, cuánto tiempo.
It sure has!
Y que lo digas.
Did you change your shampoo, Nagafuji?
¿Has cambiado de champú, Nagafuji?
Well, I spent the night at Hino's place yesterday,
Es que ayer me quedé en casa de Hino
and took a bath there this morning.
y me he bañado allí esta mañana.
Look, you don't really have to talk about that now.
Oye, no hacía falta que lo contaras.
Come on, it's our turn.
Venga, nos toca.
Okay.
Vale.
Good luck out there.
Buena suerte.
Staying at someone's house...
Quedarse en casa de alguien,
Then using their bath and then heading right to school...
usar su baño y venir al insti…
C-Can I come over, too?
¿Yo también puedo ir?
And spend the night.
Y pasar la noche.
Y-Your place, Shimamura.
En la tuya.
Why?
¿Por qué?
Well, uh...
Bueno, es que…
I mean, our bathtub's tiny.
Nuestra bañera es pequeña.
I don't really care about the bath.
No me importa.
Wait, do I? No, I think it does matter...
¿O sí? Creo que sí que importa.
Maybe it does matter...
Puede que sí importe…
Adachi?
¿Adachi?
That doesn't really matter... But I want to spend the night!
Eso da igual. Solo quiero quedarme a dormir.
But why?
Pero ¿por qué?
B-Because I want to be closer to you, Shimamura...
Porque quiero estar cerca de ti, Shimamura.
Are we not close already? I had no idea.
¿No somos ya bastante cercanas? No tenía ni idea.
No, we are, we are!
¡No, sí que lo somos!
I think... But I want to be closer.
Pero quiero estar… más cerca.
Do you get closer by spending the night, though?
¿Y crees que lo vas a conseguir durmiendo?
Well, whatever.
Bueno, da igual.
A-Adachi?
¿Adachi?
Under the pretense of discussing me spending the night,
Con la excusa de pasar la noche
I got to hang out with Shimamura after school... Wow.
he podido salir con Shimamura después del insti.
Spending the night is awesome.
Va a ser la leche.
So...
Entonces…
Do you want to come over to my place this Saturday or Sunday?
¿Quieres venirte el sábado o el domingo?
T-Two days off...
Los dos días
And spending the night two nights...
con sus dos noches…
You want to stay at my place that long?
¿Quieres quedarte tanto tiempo?
Just so you know, my place isn't an inn.
Que sepas que mi casa no es una pensión.
What about work?
¿Y el trabajo?
I'll go to work... um, from your place.
Iré a trabajar desde tu casa.
Mm-hm.
Vale.
Though there's probably going to be one more when we get to my place.
Aunque seguro que habrá más gente cuando lleguemos.
I'm not sure why, but it feels like I have two or three little sisters now.
No sé por qué, pero parece como si tuviera dos o tres hermanas.
You mean me, too?
¿Te refieres a mí?
Her little sister... Shimamura Sakura.
Su hermana Sakura Shimamura.
It's like an alliteration.
Es como una aliteración.
We'd be even closer than friends then,
Seríamos más que amigas
and that part's fine...
y eso está bien, pero…
But then I think we'd get too close and she'd notice me even less.
Creo que cuanto más me acerque, menos se daría cuenta de mi presencia.
"Change of underwear Socks 4? 5? PJs (Under shirt and track pants) Food: Bread & Instant ramen"
Cambio de muda ¿4 o 5 calcetines? Pijamas (camiseta y pantalones de deporte) Comida: Pan y fideos instantáneos
Here's all the stuff I'll need to buy...
He apuntado lo que tengo que comprar…
And then, I just need something to make sure Shimamura doesn't get bored.
Solo me queda asegurarme de que Shimamura no se aburre.
Yeah, that's not going to work.
No va a funcionar.
If we can't think of anything to do, I guess we can just watch TV together.
Si no tenemos nada que hacer, acabaremos viendo la tele juntas.
Maybe, just maybe...
Puede que quizás…
The same thing will happen and hopefully, I won't run away again.
Si ocurre lo mismo, espero no salir corriendo.
I'm not going to run away!
¡No voy a huir!
G-Good morning...
Buenos días…
You know...
Oye…
Uh... You seem to have a lot of stuff.
Creo que vas muy cargada.
You do realize you're not moving, right? It's a bit much.
Sabes que no te mudas, ¿verdad? Es demasiado.
You think so?
¿Eso crees?
Also, aren't you early? It's still 8 AM.
Además, ¿no es un poco temprano? Solo son las ocho.
S-Sorry. Were you sleeping?
Perdona, ¿estabas dormida?
Yup, you woke me up.
Sí, me has despertado.
Sorry.
Lo siento.
Eh, it's fine.
No pasa nada.
You're always so punctual, Adachi. That's good.
Siempre eres muy puntual y eso es bueno.
I was actually here at 7 AM, but I figured that was a bit too early.
La verdad es que llegué a las siete, pero supuse que era muy temprano.
I can't tell her I was just wandering around on my bike for an hour.
No le puedo decir que llevo una hora dando vueltas en la bici.
That's probably the only weird part of this, so...
Sí que eres extraña, pero…
Anyway, welcome.
Bueno, bienvenida.
Come in.
Pasa.
Th-Thanks...
Gracias…
You remember my friend, don't you?
¿Te acuerdas de mi amiga?
H-Hi...
Hola…
She's being a good girl today.
Hoy está de buenas.
Is the room upstairs okay? Or well... That's the only open room we have.
¿Te viene bien el cuarto de arriba? Es el único que tenemos libre.
Oh? Did you not want to go upstairs?
¿No querías ir arriba?
Not exactly...
No del todo…
I guess I won't be staying in the same room as you...
Parece que no voy a quedarme en tu habitación…
You want to stay in the same room as me?
¿Quieres quedarte en mi cuarto?
I'm fine with it, but I don't think my little sister will like that. Sorry.
A mí me da igual, pero creo que a mi hermana no, perdona.
There was no way this was all going to go as I planned.
Era imposible que saliera como planeaba.
I'm not sure if Shimamura's okay with me staying in her room...
No estoy segura de si le gustaría que me quedara en su habitación.
I'm fine with it, but I don't think my little sister will like that.
A mí me da igual, pero creo que a mi hermana no, perdona.
I'm fine with it... I'm fine with it...
A mí me da igual, a mí me da igual…
Or maybe she is!
O puede que le importe.
Y-Yes?
¿Sí?
What do you want to do for breakfast? Did you already eat?
¿Quieres desayunar o has comido ya?
Don't worry. I came prepared.
No te preocupes, he venido preparada.
"Long Long Sticks"
Rebanadas grandes
Hey, hey, hey...
Oye…
What? My cooking's not good enough for you?
¿Lo que he preparado no es de tu gusto?
Oh, no. I'll have some. Thank you very much...
No, gracias, comeré.
Dig in.
Adelante.
So, Adachi,
Vaya, Adachi,
you probably actually go to school unlike this daughter of mine.
tú sí que parece que vas al insti, no como mi hija.
No, I, uh...
No, yo…
Adachi's in the same boat.
Adachi es igual que yo.
Oh, really?
¿Ah, sí?
She looks like a nice, quiet girl, unlike my delinquent over here.
Pues parece tímida y buena, no como esta delincuente.
Oh, shut up.
Cállate.
Shimamura's more of a good girl than I am.
Shimamura es más buena que yo.
Good girl...?
¿Más buena?
I see. So you must be older, Adachi.
Ya veo. Seguro que tú eres mayor que ella.
That's not true.
Eso no es verdad.
Thanks for the grub.
Gracias por la comida.
Come in.
Pasa.
Um, are you mad?
¿Estás enfadada?
About what?
¿Por qué?
Oh, earlier? My mom's always like that, so there's no point in getting mad.
¿Por lo de antes? Mi madre es así, no tiene sentido enfadarme.
So that's just how their relationship is.
Ya veo cómo se llevan.
More importantly, Adachi...
Por cierto, Adachi.
What should we do now?
¿Qué hacemos?
I wonder how long it's been since I was able to feel
¿Cuánto tiempo hace que no siento
that days off were actually special?
que los días libres eran tan especiales?
Yesterday, the first day I stayed over,
Ayer fue el primer día que me quedé,
really did end with nothing happening.
pero no pasó nada especial.
W-Well, I'll see you later.
Bueno, adiós.
Have a good day!
Que tengas un buen día.
Thanks.
Gracias.
Nothing special with Shimamura actually happened.
No ha pasado nada especial con Shimamura.
We were just there together.
Nada más que pasamos tiempo juntas.
Meat was really cheap at the supermarket today.
Puede que estar con ella sea lo ideal, pero…
But...
Pero…
I-I'm going to do my best!
¡Voy a darlo todo!
Yeah, you do that.
Sí, hazlo.
Shimamura laughed.
Se ha reído.
Today might be a good day after all.
Puede que hoy vaya a ser un buen día.
But then again,
Pero ayer
it's not like absolutely nothing happened yesterday.
no pasó absolutamente nada.
Not exactly.
No del todo.
Hogetsu, hurry up, and take a bath.
Hogetsu, date prisa y báñate.
You go right to bed whenever you get full.
Vas a dormirte con el estómago lleno.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
Sí, sí, claro.
Thank you for the meal...
Gracias por la comida…
Really? You brought that, too?
-¿También has traído eso? -Su cuarto está en la primera planta,
but she naturally came to my room.
pero ha venido al mío.
That made me so happy.
Eso me puso contenta.
I'm not exactly towards who,
Me sentí superior,
but I felt superior towards them.
aunque no sabía a quién.
So, at that moment...
Por eso, en aquel momento…
I got a little bold.
me envalentoné.
Can I... um, sit between your legs?
¿Puedo sentarme entre tus piernas?
As long as you don't
Sí, siempre y cuando
run away this time.
no huyas esta vez.
Here you go.
Venga.
O-Okay, sure.
Vale.
D-Don't mind if I do...
Allá voy.
You're not going to scooch closer?
¿No vas a acurrucarte más cerca?
Sure. Then, excuse me.
Vale, con permiso.
So soft... Eek.
Qué blandita…
Th-There's no reason to panic. Shimamura's a girl, but so am I... yeah.
No te asustes. Aunque las dos seamos chicas…
Sh-Shimamura...
Shimamura…
I guess she does fall asleep right after eating...
Parece que se duerme nada más comer.
Huh? What's up? Why do you have a change of clothes?
¿Qué pasa? ¿Por qué traes toallas?
Oh, a bath.
Ah, es por el baño.
You want to take one first? That's rare.
¿Quieres bañarte tú la primera? Qué extraño.
Let's take one together.
Vamos a bañarnos juntas.
Huh? Where'd that come from? I thought you said you're embarrassed to.
¿Y eso a qué viene? Pensaba que te daba vergüenza.
It's okay sometimes... Come on.
De vez en cuando no hace daño… Venga.
Huh? Wait...
¿Eh? Espera…
Uh...
Oye…
I guess I'm going...
Venga, voy.
Shimamura...
Shimamura…
Stop daydreaming.
Espabila.
Y-Yes, ma'am.
Sí.
Ahem. Thanks for having me over... or maybe I should say, "I'm home."
Con permiso… ¿O debería decir "ya he vuelto"?
Oh, Adachi?
¿Adachi?
Y-Yes!
¡Sí!
Well, well, welcome home.
Vaya, bienvenida.
I-I've returned...
Ya he vuelto…
My daughter's out right now. She said something about shopping.
Mi hija ha salido. Ha dicho que iba a comprar algo.
Oh, I see.
Ah, vale.
She should be back soon, though.
Pero volverá pronto.
She can be pretty lazy.
A veces es un poco vaga.
She's always been a sleepyhead ever since she was little.
Desde pequeña siempre le ha gustado dormir.
She really does sleep a lot like a koala.
Duerme más que un koala.
Oh, yeah. How's she doing at school?
Por cierto, ¿cómo le va en el instituto?
Is she actually going to class?
¿Va a clase?
Y-Yes...
Sí…
Well, that's good. She tends to be lazy,
Eso es bueno. Le encanta holgazanear,
so it must be hard to get her to do anything.
así que debe ser duro que haga algo.
Huh? Not at all. Actually, it's the opposite.
¿Eh? No, para nada, más bien es al contrario.
The opposite?
¿Al contrario?
She always leads... Is that the right word? She always leads me around.
Ella es siempre la que lleva… ¿se podría decir que las riendas?
That's actually surprising.
Vaya, qué sorpresa.
I'm home. Oh, welcome back, Adachi.
Ya he vuelto. Anda, hola, Adachi.
I'm back.
Ya he vuelto.
WB.
Bienvenida.
I see you're both enjoying some dango.
Veo que estáis comiendo dango.
You didn't say anything weird to her, did you?
No le habrás contado nada raro, ¿no?
I guess upstairs works.
Nos vemos arriba.
Now that I look at it,
Ahora que lo pienso,
I think "lead" really was the right term.
lo de llevar las riendas era el término adecuado.
I pretty much follow Shimamura around like her little puppy dog.
Sigo a Shimamura como si fuera su perrito.
Oh, sit there.
Ah, siéntate.
O-Okay.
Vale.
Now, lower your head and bend down a bit.
Ahora agacha la cabeza e inclínate.
Huh? L-Like this?
¿Eh? ¿Así?
Stay just like that for a sec.
Quédate así un momento.
And then, we go like this...
Y ahora ponemos esto…
And there we go.
Y ya está.
Yup. Now you have the same hairstyle as me.
Ahora tienes el mismo peinado que yo.
A moment, please.
Un segundo.
Here.
Toma.
My hair color's starting to match yours,
Intuyo que nos pareceríamos bastante
so I figured we'd end up looking a lot alike.
porque mi pelo está empezando a ser como el tuyo.
Let's see... Hm.
Veamos…
Maybe we don't look that much alike.
Puede que a lo mejor no nos parezcamos tanto.
Oh, yeah. You can have that hairclip.
Bueno, puedes quedarte con la horquilla.
But that...
Pero…
But that means we're matching!
¡Pero eso significa que vamos a juego!
I-I... Sh-Shimamura, I...
Yo… Shimamura…
I... wuv...
Estás…
You look wuvly!
¡Estás encantadora!
Wuvly, eh?
¿Encantadora?
You look lovely, yes.
Sí, estás muy guapa.
We did this before, by the way.
Esto ya ha pasado antes.
You're so funny.
Qué graciosa eres.
Let's stretch out those cheeks.
Estira esas mejillas.
L-Let's not.
Mejor que no.
Shimamura.
Shimamura.
So today...
Hoy…
Do you want to sleep together today?!
¿Quieres que durmamos juntas hoy?
Uh, sure?
Por mí vale...
She didn't even hesitate. Then actually...
No ha dudado. En ese caso…
I should've suggested this yesterday, too!
Debería haberlo sugerido ya ayer.
But will it be okay?
Pero ¿te parece bien?
What?
¿Qué?
Your sister sleeping on her own.
Tu hermana va a dormir sola.
Oh, don't worry.
No te preocupes.
Because she has a friend sleeping over today, too.
Una amiga ha venido a dormir con ella.
Little?
Oye.
I shall teach you about the universe, Little.
Hoy voy a enseñarte cosas del universo.
Th-The universe?
¿Universo?
Yes.
Sí.
First, my kind tends to live an average of 800 million years,
En primer lugar, los de mis especie solemos vivir unos 800 millones de años,
so I belong to species that lives for a much longer time.
así que solemos vivir mucho más tiempo que los humanos.
And...
Además…
Okay, I'm turning off the lights.
Voy a apagar las luces.
Okay.
Vale.
Night.
Buenas noches.
What's wrong?
¿Qué pasa?
I-I was just wondering if you were really asleep...
Estaba comprobando si estabas dormida.
Well, yeah. I'm in my futon.
Bueno, estoy en el futón.
Right...
Ya veo…
I don't want to grow more distant with Shimamura.
No quiero alejarme más de ella.
Three, two, one. My courage is trying to tell me to go.
Tres, dos, uno… Mi valor me está diciendo que me lance.
My courage is taking the initiative, and kicking me in the ass.
Mi valor está tomando la iniciativa y animándome.
You fell like a bug.
Pareces un insecto.
Want to sleep together?
¿Quieres que durmamos juntas?
The universe... The universe...
El universo… El universo…
How do you like your Big Sis's shoulder pillow?
¿Te gusto como almohada?
I...
Yo…
I?
¿Qué?
I feel like I'm going to cry.
Tengo ganas de llorar.
Your hair's still a bit wet.
Todavía tienes el pelo húmedo.
There's something about that warmth you feel when it's wet that feels nice.
Esa calidez que se siente cuando aún lo tienes mojado sienta bien.
Can I have my arm back now?
¿Me devuelves mi brazo?
Not yet.
Todavía no.
How much longer?
¿Cuándo lo harás?
Until I fall asleep.
Cuando me duerma.
What am I ever going to do with you?
¿Qué voy a hacer contigo?
Oh, yeah. We're changing desks tomorrow.
Ah, mañana nos cambian de pupitres.
Huh? We are?
¿Ah, sí?
Oh, you didn't know because you skipped class.
No lo sabías porque te has saltado las clases.
Adachi?
¿Adachi?
It'd be great if we could sit this close.
Ojalá pudiéramos sentarnos así de cerca.
Er, I'm sure there'd be a few problems if we sat this close...
Creo que nos meteríamos en líos si nos sentáramos tan cerca…
What will be, will be.
Lo que tenga que ser, será.
Let's eat lunch together tomorrow.
Almorcemos juntas mañana.
Yeah, of course. So relax, and go to sleep.
Por supuesto. Ahora relájate y duerme.
Adachi... Goodnight.
Adachi, buenas noches.
Goodnight.
Buenas noches.
We're heading out.
Nos vamos.
Hold your horses.
Esperad.
Take these with you.
Llevaos esto.
What are these?
¿Qué es?
Can't you tell?
¿No lo ves?
Packed lunches are making a comeback!
¡Volvemos a la comida preparada en casa!
Wait, why though?
¿Por qué?
Ugh, why are you such a pain?!
No te quejes.
By the way, I think this is the first time we've gone to school together.
Por cierto, creo que es la primera vez que vamos juntas al insti.
I think so.
Eso creo.
Please let me sit near Shimamura.
Quiero sentarme cerca de Shimamura.
Please let me sit near Shimamura...
Quiero sentarme cerca de Shimamura…
Please let me...
Quiero sentarme…
I wonder how much praying actually helps in real life.
¿Cuánto ayuda rezar en la vida real?
Adachi, eyes up front.
Adachi, mira al frente.
I guess finding that out is half the fun.
Supongo que parte de la gracia es averiguarlo.
Yeah, this is sorta plain.
Sí, es bastante sencillo.
It's not like we got that much closer, and we didn't move that much away.
No estamos tan cerca, pero tampoco nos han puesto tan lejos.
"Delinquent" "Adachi"
Delincuente
And before I knew it, it had already been a month since we became second-years.
Cuando me di cuenta, ya había pasado un mes desde que entramos en segundo.
I'll only have one more April in high school.
Solo me queda un abril más en el insti.
Then it'll be May, then June... The time we have isn't infinite.
Pronto será mayo, junio… El tiempo que tenemos no es infinito.
Yummy!
¡Qué rico!
Someday... Yes, someday,
Algún día… Sí, algún día,
even if I can't imagine it clearly,
aunque no lo pueda ver con claridad,
the future is inevitable. A world where there'll be no spring breaks.
el futuro es inevitable. Un mundo sin vacaciones de primavera.
Or perhaps, a future where there's no one next to me.
O, quizás, un futuro donde no haya nadie a mi lado.
I'll be walking down
Yo también
a spring path while looking up at the cherry blossoms whether I want to or not.
caminaré mientras miro cómo florecen los cerezos, quiera o no.
Shimamura!
¡Shimamura!
And until then,
Hasta entonces,
I guess I'll settle for the cherry blossom that's right in front of me.
me conformaré con los cerezos en flor que tengo delante de mí.
I don't mind it at all.
No me importa.
It's the end of April. There aren't any more cherry blossoms anywhere.
Estamos a finales de abril y ya no quedan cerezos floreciendo.
And that's why... I'll need Adachi to be my cherry blossom.
Por eso… necesito que Adachi sea mi cerezo en flor.
Her profile will always...
Su perfil siempre será…